[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我认为我们可以做得更好
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I think we can do better than that and
我认为我们做得更好的方法是回到模块模式。
I think the way we do better is by going back to the module pattern.
我们可以把任何一堆东西放在一个函数里面
That we can take any bunch of stuff and put it inside of a function and
立即调用它，它做同样的事情，除了在这个空间中，
invoke it immediately and it does the same thing except that in this space,
我们不是在创建全局变量。
we're not creating global variables.
这种东西在创造中不会泄漏，在那里它是一个危险和危险的地方。
This stuff is not leaking out in creation where it's a danger and a hazard.
所以我们可以用这个模式来制作东西。
So we can make stuff using this pattern.
例如，我想创建一个singleton。
For example I want to make a singleton.
我想创建一个包含两个方法的对象实例，
I want to make one instance of an object containing two methods,
第一方法和第二方法，以及
first method and second method, and
我希望这两个方法共享私有变量和私有函数。
I want those two methods to share private variables and private functions.
在JavaScript中，没有简单的方法可以获得隐私，除了
In JavaScript there is no easy way to get privacy except
当你用模块或
when you're doing this stuff with with module or
功能模块，因为每个功能都有一个功能范围。
function modules because each function has a function scope.
这是一个真正有效的容器
Which is a really effective container for
保持任何东西都不会泄漏出功能范围。
keeping stuff that nothing leaks out of function scope ever.
宇宙中没有力量可以强制一个函数
There's no force in the universe that can force a function
泄露其范围内持有的内容。
to leak what is held in its scope.
我们可以利用这一点。
And we can take advantage of that.
这是一个非常好的模式，所以我要存储的是Singleton，
And it's a very nice pattern so what I'm going to store in singleton,
不是这个外部函数，因为我要立即调用那个函数。
is not this outer function because I'm going to invoke that function immediately.
我要存储的是它的返回值，
What I'm going to store will be its return value,
这个对象包含两个方法。
which is this object containing two methods.
这两种方法将关闭私有国家。
And those two methods will close over the private state.
这两种方法将共享私有国家。
And those two methods will share that private state.
如果一个人改变了这些私有变量中的一个，
If one changes one of those private variables,
另一个，下次他看那个变量时，他会看到变化。
the other, next time he looks at that variable, he will see the change.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：在我们弄清楚如何使用
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Before we figured out how to do this stuff with functions in
JavaScript，私有变量和
JavaScript, the private variable and
私有函数可能是全局变量，那里没有隐私。
private function would have been global variables, and there is no privacy there.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：与经典相比，这是一件好事
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And one nice thing about this compared to a classical
语言，在古典语言中，如果你想做一个独生子女，
language, in a classical language if you want to make a singleton,
你仍然需要制作一个类，仅仅为了制作一件东西，这需要做很多工作。
you still have to make a class, which is a lot of work just to make one thing.
而在JavaScript中，这些都不是很有用。
Whereas in JavaScript none of these are very much work.
在这个模式上有很多变化。
And there are lots of variations on this pattern.
例如，我可能有，而不是返回我想拥有的对象
For example I might have, instead of returning an object I want to have
一个全局变量，它将成为我的应用程序中所有内容的容器。
a global variable which is going to be the container of everything in my application.
它将是这个物体，它是一切事物的根源。
It's going to be this one object which is the root of everything.
我想要增强它，我想给我们的全球添加一个有条不紊的属性
And I want to enhance it, I want to add a methodical property to our global
对象，其中包含共享此私有状态的这两个方法。
object that has these two methods in it which share this private state.
我们可以很容易做到。
And we can do that easily.
所以我们不需要仅仅为了制造一个类而创建一个类，同样有很多和
So we don't have to make a class just to make one off, and again there are lots and
在这个模式上有很多变化，这是一个非常丰富的模式。
lots of variations on this pattern, it's a very rich pattern.
同样，这是有效的，因为我们立即调用了函数。
And again this works because we're invoking the function immediately.
但如果我们不立即调用函数，
But if we don't invoke the function immediately,
然后我们可以保留这个函数并创建许多实例。
then we can hold onto that function and make lots of instances.
那就这么做吧。
So let's do that.
这个模块模式很容易转换成一个强大的构造函数模式。
This module pattern is easily transformed into a powerful constructor pattern.
食谱是这样的。
So here's the recipe.
第一步，我们将使用所有技术制作一个对象，
Step 1, we're gonna make an object using all of the techniques,
任何可用于制造物体的技术。
any of the techniques available for making objects.
我们可以使用Object文字，我们可以使用new，我们可以使用Object.create。
We can use an object literal, we can use new, we can use Object.create.
我们可以调用这些功率构造函数中的另一个。
We can call another of these power constructors.
只要我们能得到一个物体，我们就能得到一个物体。
Any way we can get an object, we get an object.
第二步，我们将定义一些变量和函数。
Step 2, we will define some variables and functions.
这些将成为我们对象的私有成员。
These will become the private members of our object.
步骤3，我们将用特权方法扩充对象。
Step 3, we will augment the object with privileged methods.
特权方法是对象的公开可用方法
A privileged method is a publicly available method of an object
关闭了私人物品。
which closes over the private stuff.
步骤4，我们返回对象。
And step 4, we return the object.
所以这是一个非常简单的食谱。
So it's a pretty simple recipe.
它太抽象了，搞不懂，对吧？
It's way too abstract to make sense out of it, right?
所以我们需要再深入一点。
So we need to go a little deeper.
所以让我们把它变成一个模板。
So let's turn it into a template.
所以第一步，我要做一个构造函数。
So step 1, I'm going to make a constructor function.
我现在用小写的c而不是大写的c拼写构造函数，
And I'm spelling constructor now with a lowercase c instead of an uppercase c,
因为这种形式的构造函数不关心新的前缀。
because this form of constructor does not care about the new prefix.
如果你用一个新的前缀调用这个函数，它的运行速度会稍微慢一点，
If you call this function with a new prefix it will run a little bit slower,
但它仍然会做正确的事情。
but it will still do exactly the right thing.
所以，这样我们就不用担心别人
So, this way we don't have to worry about people
忘记新的前缀，因为没有什么会出错。
forgetting the new prefix cuz nothing can go wrong.
那么我建议传入一个规范对象。
Then I'm gonna recommend passing in a specification object.
通常编写构造函数的方式是直接传入
The way you normally write constructors is you'll just pass in
一些用逗号分隔的东西。
some number of things separated by commas.
几年前，我设计了一个有十个参数的构造函数，
Some years ago, I designed a constructor that had ten arguments in it,
这是一个问题，因为没有人能记住他们的顺序。
which was a problem because nobody could remember what order they went in.
所以它真的很难使用
So it was really hard to use and
后来发现没有人使用第三个参数。
then it turned out nobody used the third parameter.
但我们不能把它取出来，对吧，
But we couldn't take it out, right,
因为如果我们把这个参数去掉，那么所有的代码都会被破坏。
cuz if we took that argument out, then all of the code would break.
因此，人们不得不永远不必要地使用第三个参数。
And so people had to use the third parameter unnecessarily forever.
那真的很糟糕很脆弱。
That was really awful and brittle.
所以，我要做的是说用一个对象文字传入一个对象。
So, what I would do instead is say pass in an object using an object literal.
因此，只需再添加两个字符，我们现在就可以获得命名参数。
So, by just adding two more characters, we can now have named parameters.
我可以给每个参数起一个名字so，调用是自记录的，所以
I can give each of the parameters a name so, the call is self documenting, so
我们可以看到传入的是什么。
we can see what's getting passed in.
我们可以任何顺序拥有它们，如果我们省略了一些东西，我们可以有很好的默认值，
We can have them in any order, if we leave things out we can have nice defaults,
如果结果是某些参数变得不必要，我们只需忽略它们。
if it turns out some parameters become unnecessary we simply ignore them.
我们有很大的力量可以操纵物体
We have lots of power in the way that we can manipulate objects so
我会利用这一点。
I would take advantage of that.
此外，我们可以从JSON有效负载中获取规范对象。
Also, we could get the specification object from a JSON payload.
因此，我们可能有一些存储，我们希望使用构造函数
So we might have some store that we want to use the constructor to
重建对象。
reconstitute the object.
我们也可以这样做。
We can do that as well.
或导致跨网络创建对象
Or to cause the creation of objects across the network
使用规范通过JSON通过线路传递。
using specifications to get passed over the wire through JSON.
然后我将调用另一个构造函数来创建一个对象
Then I'm going to call another constructor to make an object and
我也会把同样的规范对象传递给他。
I'm gonna pass the same specification object to him as well.
因此，其他构造函数可能会使用
So it maybe that that other constructor will make use of some properties in
规范对象，我不需要，但对他来说是有意义的。
the specification object that I don't need but that makes sense to him.
如果我们都需要什么，我们就一起分享。
And if there's anything we both need we're sharing it.
我以前把这种寄生遗传称为我们将要称之为
I used to call this parasitic inheritance where we're gonna call
另一个构造者，我们要为它的工作而功劳。
another constructor and we're gonna take credit for its work.
我的灵感来自于一只黄蜂，它在活的蜘蛛体内产卵。
I was inspired by a wasp that lays its eggs in the bodies of live spiders.
所以蜘蛛做了大部分创建实例的工作，但是
So the spider does most of the work of making instances but
黄蜂得到了所有的荣誉，会做一些类似的事情。
the wasp gets all the credit, gonna do something like that.
然后我会得到另一个制造者所做的结果，并且
And then I'll take the result of what the other maker did, and
将其放入一个名为that的变量中。
put it in a variable called that.
我不能把它放在叫做this的东西里，因为这是一个保留字。
I can't put it in something called this because this is a reserved word.
然后我可以创建我的成员变量。
Then I can create my member variables.
我可以创建任意多的成员变量。
I can create as many member variables as I want.
因为它们将被保存在函数范围内，
And because they're gonna be held in the function scope,
它们在对象外部不可见，仅在对象内部可见。
they're not visible outside of the object, they're only visible inside the object.
我将创建我的私有方法和我的私有方法
I will create my private methods, and my private methods
将有权访问成员变量的规范对象和
will have access to the specification object to the member variables and
其他方法也一样。
to the other methods as well.
我在这里不用这个，不需要这个，
I do not use this in here, don't need this,
所以代码会变得更小更干净。
so the code's going to be a little bit smaller and cleaner.
以及我需要公开的这些方法中的任何一种，
And any of these methods that I need to be public,
我只是将它们分配给传出对象。
I simply assign them to the outgoing object.
最后一步，我返回对象。
And the last step, I return the object.
就是这样。
And that's it.
这是一个非常灵活的模式，有很多
And it's a very flexible pattern, there are lots and
很多变化，但这是基本的核心思想，我们正在采取
lots of variations on this but this is the basic core idea, that we're taking
使用闭包以便在对象内提供私有状态。
use of closure in order to provide private state within the object.